<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>Mixed Students in Higher Education</title>
    <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject" />
    <updated>2022-12-01T13:06:37-08:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Resources</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/resources/"/>
        <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/resources/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T12:02:58-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/5/MSU.jpeg" alt="" />
                    For any mixed student struggling with their identity and perceived fraudulence: Resources at UCLA Bruin Resource Center: https://brc.ucla.edu UCLA Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Center: https://equity.ucla.edu Mixed Student Union: https://community.ucla.edu/studentorg/1237 Here is Yuliana Barrón Perez's 2022 Commencement speech that encourages higher education: General Resources Mixed Teens&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/5/MSU.jpeg" alt="" />
                <h2 class="align-center">For any mixed student struggling with their identity and perceived fraudulence:</h2>
<h3 class="align-center">Resources at UCLA</h3>
<ul>
<li class="align-left"><span class="JsGRdQ">Bruin Resource Center: <a href="https://brc.ucla.edu">https://brc.ucla.edu</a></span></li>
<li class="align-left"><span class="JsGRdQ">UCLA Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion Center: <a href="https://equity.ucla.edu">https://equity.ucla.edu</a></span></li>
<li class="align-left">Mixed Student Union: <a href="https://community.ucla.edu/studentorg/1237" style="font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);">https://community.ucla.edu/studentorg/1237</a><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit; font-weight: var(--font-weight-normal);"> </span></li>
<li>Here is Yuliana Barrón Perez's 2022 Commencement speech that encourages higher education:<div class="post__iframe"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="314" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/uwlT4jAarbg" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></div></li>
</ul>
<h3 class="align-center"><span class="JsGRdQ">General Resources</span></h3>
<ul>
<li><span class="JsGRdQ">Mixed Teens in America: <a href="https://www.parents.com/parenting/better-parenting/teenagers/what-its-like-to-grow-up-biracial-in-america-today/">https://www.parents.com/parenting/better-parenting/teenagers/what-its-like-to-grow-up-biracial-in-america-today/</a></span></li>
<li class="align-left"><span class="JsGRdQ">The Mixed Experience in American: <a href="https://www.vox.com/first-person/21734156/kamala-harris-mixed-race-biracial-multiracial">https://www.vox.com/first-person/21734156/kamala-harris-mixed-race-biracial-multiracial</a> </span></li>
<li class="align-left"><span class="JsGRdQ">Resources to explore identity questions: <a href="https://socialworklicensemap.com/blog/resources-explore-multicultural-identity-mixed-race-families/#first-person-perspectives">https://socialworklicensemap.com/blog/resources-explore-multicultural-identity-mixed-race-families/#first-person-perspectives</a> </span></li>
</ul>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Interview with a Mixed Student at UCLA</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/interview-with-a-mixed-student-at-ucla/"/>
        <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/interview-with-a-mixed-student-at-ucla/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T12:47:29-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/4/IMG_4158.JPG" alt="" />
                    Podcast with a fellow mixed UCLA student Listen to "Interview with a Mixed UCLA Student" on Spreaker. Alright! Hello my name is Sofia, I am a third-year Statistics Undergraduate student at UCLA, and I am here to interview... Hi guys! I'm Midori and I am&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/4/IMG_4158.JPG" alt="" />
                <h2 class="align-center">Podcast with a fellow mixed UCLA student</h2>
<p><a class="spreaker-player" href="https://www.spreaker.com/episode/52070621" data-resource="episode_id=52070621" data-width="100%" data-height="200px" data-theme="light" data-playlist="false" data-playlist-continuous="false" data-chapters-image="true" data-episode-image-position="right" data-hide-logo="false" data-hide-likes="false" data-hide-comments="false" data-hide-sharing="false" data-hide-download="true">Listen to "Interview with a Mixed UCLA Student" on Spreaker.</a></p>
<h3 class="align-center">Transcript</h3>
<p>Alright! Hello my name is Sofia, I am a third-year Statistics Undergraduate student at UCLA, and I am here to interview...</p>
<p>Hi guys! I'm Midori and I am a fourth-year Physiological Sciences major and minor in Global Health. Thanks so much for having me Sofia.</p>
<p>Of course! Alright, we are just going to interview Midori about her upbringing as a mixed student and just some scenarios that she had to deal with while growing up. My first question for you is, how did being a mixed student affect your upbringing?</p>
<p>Yeah! So I am half Japanese and half White. Being mixed really affected my identity growing up, I never felt like I belonged in either of those categories. However, I feel like a lot of my peers and friends labeled me as Japanese and kind of ignored the other side of me. So I definitely dealt with a lot of discrimination for being Japanese even though I am mixed as well. </p>
<p>Wow! Thank you for sharing that, I really appreciate it. My next question would be, how had being mixed affected your time at UCLA and has UCLA offered enough materials and resources for you to feel included on campus?</p>
<p>I never really felt in touch with my identity and I wish I did join a lot more mixed organizations. I definitely attended a couple of Mixed Student Union club meetings which were really fun and allowed me to explore how I felt about it. I never really thought about what it meant to me to be mixed, and I think I identified more with my Japanese side because of how I grew up.</p>
<p>Awesome! Yeah, I definitely have felt the same way. My last question to you would be how has being mixed affected your mental health?</p>
<p>Being mixed, again, definitely affected how I felt who I was and my identity, and not really feeling like I was apart of something specific. I never felt like I fit in with the Japanese community or the White community as well. But, if I visited the Japanese side of my family I felt more connected to them and the same with my White family. I also definitely look different than both sides of my family, a lot of people do not believe I am related to my mom completely or my dad or even my grandparents completely, and I felt like that definitely effected how I view myself. I never really found a community that felt right with me.</p>
<p>Yeah, and I feel like that is how a lot of Mixed students feel, and thank you so much for sharing your story Midori. That will be it for our podcast today, thanks for listening!</p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Interactive Example</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/interactive-example/"/>
        <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/interactive-example/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T12:04:28-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/3/Screen-Shot-2022-10-19-at-2.49.00-PM.png" alt="" />
                    To demonstrate a struggle that a mixed student may face, I created an interactive story in the point of view of a young Chicana-identifying woman who is applying for an internship. She is an undergraduate student hoping to gain experience in the field she wants&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/3/Screen-Shot-2022-10-19-at-2.49.00-PM.png" alt="" />
                <p>To demonstrate a struggle that a mixed student may face, I created an interactive story in the point of view of a young Chicana-identifying woman who is applying for an internship. She is an undergraduate student hoping to gain experience in the field she wants to pursue a career in. However, as she is applying, she is faced with the challenge to choose ONE race/ethnicity to identify with. </p>
<p>This game is inspired by <a href="https://www.themujerista.com/the-blog/how-race-and-ethnicity-categories-in-job-applications-forms-and-the-census-ignore-the-reality-of-mixed-identities" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Mujerista</a>, revolving around an article she wrote about being mixed and the struggles that come with it.</p>
<p>Play the Virtual Interview Simulation <a href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/miniassign2DH150/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">here</a>, or stay on this page and play below!</p>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" style="width: 721px; height: 826px;" src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/miniassign2DH150/" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<h2 class="align-center">Why is Identity Important?</h2>
<p>Identity is more than a word describing your background. According to Merriam-Webster, it is "the distinguishing character or personality of an individual." A significant characteristic that defines a person's identity is their race/ethnicity, and mixed students, being more than one race/ethnicity, are faced with the challenge to choose the identity they will be accepted with most.</p>
<h2 class="align-center">Mental Health Effects</h2>
<p>As all minorities, mixed students face severe mental health effects regarding their upbringing and backlash from their communities. However, mixed students are often overlooked because many of them have traits that give them privilege; for instance, being white-passing. When I came to UCLA, I was intrigued with the amount of diversity and cultural clubs there were, but there were little resources specifically made for mixed students. Being mixed often come with the challenge of deciding which cultural affinity you resonate with most; and that is decided based on the environment you are in. In an article published by the National Library of Medicine, researchers found that "Adolescents who self-identify as more than 1 race are at higher health and behavior risks. The findings are compatible with interpreting the elevated risk of mixed race as associated with stress." Regardless of what a mixed student identifies as, there is always the chance of backlash from their communities. If you are a mixed student struggling with finding your identity, please visit our <a href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/resources/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Resources</a> tab.</p>
<p class="msg msg--info">Data provided by: <a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1448064/">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC1448064/</a> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>My Experience</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/my-experience/"/>
        <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/my-experience/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T12:03:45-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/IMG_1479_Original.JPG" alt="" />
                    This past October I created a website that tells the story of my journey to accepting and empowering my identity. I included background about myself, my journey at UCLA, an About Me page, and resources for any readers who seek them. I created my website&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/IMG_1479_Original.JPG" alt="" />
                <p><span style="color: var(--text-primary-color); font-family: var(--editor-font-family); font-size: inherit;">This past October I created a website that tells the story of my journey to accepting and empowering my identity. I included background about myself, my journey at UCLA, an About Me page, and resources for any readers who seek them. I created my website intending to share my story to help other mixed students see that they are not alone and that there are resources for them at UCLA and on the internet. I want to use this website  and the one below to spread awareness about how mixed individuals are often conflicted with their identities, and share my story on how I embraced mine in hopes of inspiring others to do the same. For more information about me and my journey, check it out below:</span></p>
<figure class="post__video"><iframe loading="lazy" style="width: 100%; height: 800px;" src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/publlisite/" data-mce-fragment="1"></iframe></figure>
<h2 class="align-center">About Me</h2>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/IMG_6715-2.PNG" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-xs.PNG 300w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-sm.PNG 480w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-md.PNG 768w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-lg.PNG 1024w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-xl.PNG 1360w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/2/responsive/IMG_6715-2-2xl.PNG 1600w"  alt="Portrait of Sofia Villalpando at UCLA" width="175" height="263"></figure>
<p>Hi! My name is Sofia Villalpando and I am a third-year undergraduate Statistics major and Digital Humanities minor student at UCLA. Being mixed has always been a struggle for me, I never felt like I belonged in either culture of my background. I created this site with the intention of encouraging mixed students to find their identity and to reassure them that they are not alone. Feel free to connect with me on <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/sofia-villalpando-b21318231/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">LinkedIn</a>!</p>
<p> </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
    <entry>
        <title>Mixed Students and Higher Education: A Guide to Supporting Identity Crises</title>
        <author>
            <name>Sofia Villalpando</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/mixed-students-and-higher-education-a-guide-to-supporting-identity-crises/"/>
        <id>https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/mixed-students-and-higher-education-a-guide-to-supporting-identity-crises/</id>

        <updated>2022-12-01T13:06:37-08:00</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/IMG_7631.JPG" alt="" />
                    Growing up in a predominantly Hispanic community as a half Mexican, half White child, I constantly thought about my identity and how I never felt included with people who shared the same background as me. My parents worked for the majority of my childhood, so&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/IMG_7631.JPG" alt="" />
                <p>Growing up in a predominantly Hispanic community as a half Mexican, half White child, I constantly thought about my identity and how I never felt included with people who shared the same background as me. My parents worked for the majority of my childhood, so my father did not have the time to teach me Spanish. The fact that I would be taught in English was also a factor, so I was raised speaking English and did not have much experience with Spanish. Not a lot of kids looked like me, and many of them asked what my background was. Questions roaming from "Why are you so hairy?" to "You can't be Mexican, why don't you speak any Spanish?" often made me feel conflicted. The absence of any cultural celebrations at school also made me feel that I could not identify with my Hispanic peers, while my physical characteristics made me feel like I could not identify as white. I was either too White to be Mexican, or too Mexican to be White. Not being able to feel comfortable with my peers because of my ethnicity and race contributed to the downfall of my mental health and performance as a student. I was constantly trying to win the approval of others, then beating myself up when I did not feel included. Until I started to attend UCLA.</p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/IMG_7659.JPG" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-xs.JPG 300w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-sm.JPG 480w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-md.JPG 768w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-lg.JPG 1024w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-xl.JPG 1360w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_7659-2xl.JPG 1600w"  alt="" width="2000" height="1333"></figure>
<p>My intention for this website is to bring attention to the mental health and social affects that being mixed has on students. There are little to no resources for students, so with this website I want to provide evidence that you are not alone if you are mixed and struggling with your identity, as well as provide resources and help to those who are in need. </p>
<p>The inspiration for this website comes from my journey to finding my identity. I did not address the issues I faced internally growing up until I was diagnosed with major depression disorder and started attending therapy. I want mixed students to know that they are not alone, while bringing awareness to the issues of identity to everyone from all backgrounds. </p>
<figure class="post__image"><img loading="lazy"  src="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/IMG_1802.JPG" sizes="100vw" srcset="https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-xs.JPG 300w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-sm.JPG 480w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-md.JPG 768w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-lg.JPG 1024w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-xl.JPG 1360w ,https://sofiavillalpando.github.io/dh150finalproject/media/posts/1/responsive/IMG_1802-2xl.JPG 1600w"  alt="" width="2000" height="1500"></figure>
<p>In this site, I review my story, provide resources for mixed students, have an interview with another UCLA student who is mixed, and provide an interactive example that I created to show the discrimination that mixed students are facing today. </p>
<p>Enjoy, and please connect with me if you have any questions, thoughts, or concerns. I would love to hear them!</p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
